SHUBHAM MISHRA

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To Build a longs term career in Research and academics with the opportunities for career growth and enhance my education and professional skills in a stable and dynamic workplace and be able to solve problems in such creative and effective manner in challenging position.

CONTACT



8808664800



8808664800



538/1, VISWAS COLONY, SAMNEGHAT LANKA, VARANASI, 221005,U.P.



biotechshubham007@gmail.com

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Biotechnology

Shoolini University, Solan, H.P. 2018 - 2020

7.2 OGPA

B.Sc. Biotechnology

Bundelkhand University, Jhansi, (U.P) 2014 - 2017

6.2 CGPA

XII (CBSE)

Bal Vidyalya Madhyamic School, Varanasi (U.P)

2013 - 2014

63%

SKILLS

- Adaptability
- Time management
- Leadership
- Communication

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

- Chess
- Travelling
- Basketball
- Bike riding

OBJECTIVE

To secure a challenging position in reputable organization to expand my learnings, knowledge, and skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apex Hospital, Varanasi

Lab technician

10 July, 2020 - 13 Dec, 2020

 Handles all technical work of Clinical Microbiology Laboratory.

Heritage Institute of Medical Sciences, Varanasi Lab technician

18 Jan, 2021 – 18 April, 2022.

- Biorad CFX96 Real Time PCR Analyzer.
- Trunat Analyzer.
- ELISA.
- Serological Testing.
 - Handle COVID-19 samples for testing.
 - RT-PCR

INTERNSHIP

❖Naxpar Pharma Pvt. Ltd.

One-month training Baddi, H.P.

❖Heritage institute of Medical Science

Three-month training in Microbiology laboratory Varanasi, U.P.

- **❖Training in Real time quantitative micro PCR system**
- ♦Training CFX96 Real time PCR system and CFX maestro software (17 march 2021)

PROJECTS

Successfully completed a project entitled as "Lacases Catalyses for the synthesis of bioactive compounds" at **Shoolini University, Solan, Himachal Pradesh.**

CERTIFICATION

IPR workshop

Participated in 2nd annual IPR workshop at Shoolini University, Solan.

 Third National Conference on Cutting edge Research and Innovation in biotechnology and other life sciences, Chandigarh University.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Age- 26 Yrs, Male

Languages known-

- English
- Hindi

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Instrumentation: UV-VIS Spectrophotometer, HPLC, ICP-MS.
- Microbiology Skills: Streaking, Culturing & Sub culturing, staining, MIC test.
- Molecular Biology skill: DNA extraction, Hepatitis C Virus Quantitative Testing, PCR, Electrophoresis, Serological tests, Chromatography techniques including HPLC, Have practical knowledge of ICP-MS.
- ❖ Bioinformatics: BLAST, FASTA, Clustal Omega. Clustal W.
- ❖ IT skills: Well versed with Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, and Excel; and have better working knowledge of MS-windows 10.